ALBERTO GAONA

Machine Learning Engineer

Nuevo Leon, México albertoo_3c@hotmail.com +52 844 594 6238 LinkedIn, GitHub, Portfolio

I have over four years of experience in deep learning, precisely computer vision. I have honed my python skills and delivered innovative machine learning solutions through the development of pipelines. As a remote worker with solid time management skills, I have conducted research in emerging technologies to contribute to an Al-powered startup.

EXPERIENCE

DPlace - Deep Learning Engineer

May 2022 - present

- Integrated machine learning algorithms to optimize a manual virtual product placement workflow.
- Built an Al service framework using python with a load-balancing algorithm to distribute user API requests.
- Conducted research on diffusion models and created pipelines for visual storytelling products.

REstyle (DPlace) - Machine Learning Engineer

Jul 2021 - Dec 2022

- Developed computer vision solutions using Pytorch for components of a patented hair try-on technology.
- Managed a three-month knowledge transfer after the sale of the technology ensuring a seamless transition.

Toshiba GCS - C++ Software Engineer 1

Oct 2019 - Jul 2021

- Solved 50+ issues in Toshiba POS base code that involved understanding complex C++ logic.
- Applied around seven technical interviews for junior and senior C++ software engineer positions.
- Collaborated through deep learning ideas with an internal team for the next generation of self-checkout.

PROJECTS

Initiative Almendra

July 2019 - Present

- Build educational resources about advanced deep learning concepts for computer vision using YouTube.
- Gave a three-hour workshop about artificial neural network basics for university's students.

More projects on my portfolio page: betogaona7.github.io

EDUCATION

Udacity (2017 - 2020)

Nanodegree, Deep Learning

Nanodegree, Artificial Intelligence & Deep Learning Specializations.

Universidad Autónoma de Coahuila (2012 - 2017)

B.S. Computer Science.

Digital Invaders (2015)

Certificate, Innovation & Technological Creativity.